Cleve Gray
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Alphabetical Files, 1936-2005, Series 2:; (Boxes 1-5, 9; 4.3 linear ft.)
  Subject files mostly consist of correspondence, but include printed material and some photographs. Among them are: Art Collection of Cleve and Francine Gray, Art in America Ceramics Project, Art in America Decorative Arts Show, Artist-Art Dealer Consignments and Visual Artists' Rights Act of 1989, Artists' Tax Equity Act of 1979, "Narcissus in Chaos," Outdoor Art at the Station, Promised Gifts to Museums, Sculpture, Threnody, Vestments, and Vietnam Protest. Other files of particular interest relate to the Estate of Hans Richter (Cleve Gray, executor), and Gray's research materials and illustrations (photographs of artists including: Nell Blaine, Lee Bontecou, Joan Brown, Elaine de Kooning, Helen Frankenthaler, Sonia Gretchoff, Grace Hartigan, and Ethel Magafan) for his Cosmopolitan article "Women - Leaders of Modern Art."
  - Abrams, Harry N., (See: Harry N. Abrams, Inc., Box 2, F 61) (Box 1)
  - Addison Gallery of American Art, 1967-1997, (See also: Correspondence, Business, Box 1, F 20) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Addison Gallery of American Art Committee, 1955-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Addison Gallery of American Art Committee, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Admired Articles," 1924-1996, undated, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
  - Ajay, Abe, 1970-1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Albright-Knox Art Gallery, 1975-1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Albright-Knox Exhibition Catalog (thank you letters), 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Aldrich Museum of Contemporary Art - Alva Gallery, 1985-2002 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Aldrich Museum of Contemporary Art
    Alexander, Brooke (re: Jasper Johns lithograph)
    Alva Gallery
  - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, 1985-1998 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - American Academy in Rome, 1985-1996, (See also: Correspondence, Business, Box 1, F 20) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - American Council of Learned Societies - Archives of American Art, 1966-1998 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    American Council of Learned Societies
    American Federation of Arts (See: Correspondence, Business, Box 1, F 20)
    The American Scholar
    Apperendimento della Stampa d'Arte
    Archives of American Art
  - Arlene McDaniel Galleries, 1983-1992 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Armstrong Gallery, 1983-1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Art Advisory Services, Inc., 1993-2001, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Art Collection of Cleve and Francine Gray, 1960-1997, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Art for Mexico, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Art in America, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Art in America Ceramics Project, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Art in America Decorative Arts Show, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Art in Embassies Program, U. S. Department of State, 1991-2002 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Art Loss Register - Art Now: New York, 1970-1997 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Art Loss Register
    Art Now: New York
  - Arte de America y España, Madrid, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Artist-Art Dealer Consignments and Visual Artists' Rights Act of 1989, 1978-1989 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Artists' Tax Equity Act of 1979, 1976-1979, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
  - Associated American Artists, 1963-1972, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Atelier Mourlot Ltd. - Barnet, Will, 1968-2002, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Atelier Mourlot Ltd.
    Audubon Artists, Inc.
    Avedon, Richard
    Barnes, Susan
    Barnet, Will
  - Barzun, Jacques, 1949-1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Barzun, Jacques, 1967-1995 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Beier, Carol, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Berrigan, Carol Natalie, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Berrigan, Philip, 1973-1989 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Berry-Hill Galleries, Inc., 1988-2003, undated, (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 40-44)
  - Beth El Temple of West Hartford, Sisterhood - Betts, Edward, 1964-1982 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Beth El Temple of West Hartford, Sisterhood
    Betsy Ross Flag and Banner Co., Inc.
    Betts, Edward
  - Betty Parsons Gallery, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 46-49)
  - Betty Parsons Gallery, 1983, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Birch, Stephen, Jr., Estate of, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Boody Fine Arts, Inc., 1985-1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Boston, Richard and Cindy - Breeskin, Adelyn, 1968-1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Boston, Richard and Cindy
    Bottom, Elliott B.
    Breeskin, Adelyn
  - Brooklyn Museum of Art, 1984-1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bruce Museum - Buckalew, Ralph, 1973-1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Bruce Museum
    Buckalew, Ralph
  - Butler Institute of American Art, 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cage, John - Cartier-Bresson, Henri, 1970-1998, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Cage, John (See also: Correspondence, Personal, Box 1, F 21)
    Calder, Alexander (See also: Correspondence, Personal, Box 1, F 21)
    Calder, Louisa
    Cambridge University Press
    Campbell, Lawrence
    Canton Artists' Guild, Inc.
    Carter, Elliott
    Cartier-Bresson, Henri
  - Central Connecticut State University, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Century Association, 1968-2001, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Chamberlain, Richard - Clevepak Corporation, 1978-1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Chamberlain, Richard
    Charles, Otis
    Clevepak Corporation (re: appraisal of Marcel Breuer tapestries)
  - Collins Communications, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Columbia University (Box 2)
    - Arts Center, 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - John Jay National Scholarship Program, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Review of Graduate Program in Painting and Sculpture, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Columbus Museum of Art - Connecticut Civil Liberties Union, 1968-1998 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Columbus Museum of Art/Columbus Gallery of Fine Arts
    Connecticut Academy of Fine Arts
    Connecticut Civil Liberties Union
  - Connecticut Commission on the Arts, 1977-1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Copley, William - Cormus, Frances, 1968-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Copley, William
    Copyright Revision Bill
    Corcoran Gallery of Art
    Cordier and Eckstrom
    Cormus, Frances
  - Correspondence, Business, 1946-1966, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Addison Gallery of American Art
    American Academy in Rome
    American Federation of Arts
    Art in America
    Art in Industry
    Art Institute of Chicago (Frederick A. Sweet, Katharine Kuh)
    Buchholz Gallery (Curt Valentin)
    Grand Central Art Galleries
    Honolulu Academy of Arts
    Jacques Seligmann and Co., Inc.
    Life
    Museum of Modern Art (Alfred H. Barr, William S. Lieberman, and Dorothy C. Miller)
    New York Times (Edward Alden Jewell)
    Princeton University, The Art Museum
    Rae, Mr.
    Staempfli Gallery, Inc.
    Syracuse University Library
    Thomas Smith Kelly Lighting
    W. R. Grace and Co. (re: Louise N. Grace)
    Whitney Museum of American Art (Herman More)
    Yale University, Division of the Arts
    Unknown and Illegible (Anne? or Arne?)
  - Correspondence, Personal, 1944-1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Cage, John
    Calder, Alexander
    Dine, Jim
    Duchamp, Marcel
    Ernst, Jimmy
    Frankenthaler, Helen
    Grace, Louise N.
    Hess, Thomas
    Kienbusch, William
    Lhote, Andre
    Maxwell, William
    Morris, George L. K.
    Motherwell, Robert
    Museum of Modern Art (Alfred H. Barr)
    New York Times (editor; John Canady)
    Newman, Barnet
    Stamos, Theodoros
    Styron, William
    Unidentified and Illegible (Isobel; Emily E. F. Steel? Skeel? or Keel?; T.D.P.)
  - Cosmopolitan Article, "Women-Leaders of Modern Art" ( (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, Research Material, and Manuscript), circa 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Illustrations (photographs of artists and art work), circa 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Blaine, Nell
      Bontecou, Lee
      Brown, Joan
      de Kooning, Elaine
      Grechtoff, Sonia
      Hartigan, Grace
      Magafan, Ethel
      Nevelson, Louise
      O'Keeffe, Georgia
  - Crawford, Ralston - Danto, Arthur C., 1967-1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Crawford, Ralston
    Cumberland College Art Gallery
    Cunningham, Charles C.
    Cunningham, Merce
    Danto, Arthur C.
  - Davis, James E., 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Davis, James E., 1966-1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - De Cordova Museum - Dehner, Dorothy, 1968-1977 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    De Cordova Museum
    Dehner, Dorothy
  - Dillenberger, Jane, 1978-1991, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Drake, Allan, 1972-1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Drury, Felix, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Duchamp, Marcel, 1967-2001, (See also: Correspondence, Personal, Box 1, F 21); Shearer, Rhonda, Box 4, F 28) (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Duchamp-Poincaré Symposium (Harvard University, 1999), 1998-2001 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Duffy, Joseph, 1968-1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Duke University Museum of Art, 1985-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Eichenberg, Fritz - Estudio Actual, 1962?-1981 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Eichenberg, Fritz
    Emmerich, André
    Ernst, Jimmy (See also: Correspondence, Personal, Box 1, F 21)
    Estudio Actual
  - Eva Cohon Gallery Ltd., 1990-1992, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Eve Mannes Gallery, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Fairweather Hardin Gallery, 1983-1987, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Farm, 1951-1960, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Farmington Public Schools, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Felt, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Ferber, Herbert, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Fogg Art Museum, Harvard University, 1971-1995, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Frankenthaler, Helen - Gabo, Miriam, 1967-1989, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
    Friends of the School of Art and Design, University of Illinois
    G. Fox and Co. Gallery
    Gabo, Miriam
  - Gabo, Naum (Box 2)
    - Book, 1970-1978 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1978, undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Galleria Pagani Exhibition, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Gallery Two Nine One, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Georges Borchardt, Inc., Literary Agent-Gervais, André, 1978-1987 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    Georges Borchardt, Inc., Literary Agent
    Gervais, André
  - Gleizes, Albert, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Goff, Bruce, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Goff, Bruce, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Goodale, James C., 1931 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Grace, Louise N., 1943-1946, (2 folders; See also: Correspondence, Personal, Box 1, F 21) (Box 2, Folder 54-55)
  - Grace, Louise N., 1944-1946, (typescript copies) (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Graduate Theological Union, Berkeley, 1995-2000 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Greater Hartford Civic and Arts Festival - Guberman, Sidney, 1974-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
    Greater Hartford Civic and Arts Festival
    Greene, Stephen
    Grey Art Gallery, New York University
    Griffin-Haller Gallery
    Grausman, Philip
    Grosman, Tatyana
    Guberman, Sidney
  - Guggenheim-Kandinsky Affair - Handman, Wynn, 1964-1976 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    Guggenheim-Kandinsky Affair
    Guston, Philip
    Handman, Wynn
  - Hank Baum Gallery/Graphics Gallery/Graphic Gallery, 1969-1980 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Hanover, Nancy - Harry N. Abrams, Inc., 1970-1998 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    Hanover, Nancy
    Harcourts Contemporary
    Harper and Row, Publishers, Inc.
    Harry N. Abrams, Inc.
  - Hartford Courant - Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, 1969-1998, undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
    Hartford Courant
    Hauser, Ernest
    Heckscher Museum
    Hess, Thomas B.
    Hirschl and Adler Galleries
    Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc., 1968-2002, undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - "Homage to Betty Parsons," 1997 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Honolulu, 1969-1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Honolulu Academy of Arts, 1969-1997, (See also: Correspondence, Business, Box 1, F 20) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - House and Garden-Instituto Mexicano Norteamericano de Relaciones Culturales, A.C., 1968-1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    House and Garden
    Hubbard, John
    Hughes, Robert
    Huxley, Paul
    Ingersoll, Thelma (Mrs. Ralph)
    Instituto Mexicano Norteamericano de Relaciones Culturales, A.C.
  - Irving Galleries, 1980-1999, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Israel, 1971-1981, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Javits, Marian B. - Jewish Museum, 1983-1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Javits, Marian B.
    Jenkins, Paul
    Jewish Museum
  - Jacques Seligmann and Co., Inc., 1949-1959, (See also: Correspondence, Business, Box 1, F 20) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Jacques Seligmann and Co., Inc., 1947-1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Jerold Morris International Gallery Limited, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Johns, Jasper - Kennedy Graphics, Inc., 1970-2000, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Johns, Jasper, undated (See also: Alexander, Brooke, re: Johns lithograph, Box 1, F 15)
    Kaplan, Jacques and Violaine Bachelier, undated
    Kass, Alan and Grace, undated
    Kennedy Galleries, Inc., 1987
    Kennedy Graphics, Inc., 1970
  - Kennedy, John F. (Cosmopolitan Gallery exhibition), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Kienbusch, William - Kramer, Nathaniel D., 1978-1989, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Kienbusch, William (See also: Correspondence, Personal, Box 1, F 21)
    Knowlton
    Kosturko, William T.
    Kramer, Nathaniel D.
  - Krannert Art Museum, University of Illinois, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Lavin, Marilyn, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Legal Documents (leases, agreements, insurance policy, etc.), 1947-1965, (Reel D314, frames 689-716) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Leonardo: International Journal of Contemporary Art, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Leslie Feely Fine Art, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Lewis, Tom and Stasia - Luers, William H., 1969-2001, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Lewis, Tom and Stasia
    LeWitt, Carol and Sol/LeWitt Collection
    Liberman, Alexander
    Lifton, Robert J.
    Lipman, Howard
    Lipman, Jean
    Litchfield County Times
    Lott, W.
    Lowy, Stephen P. (F.A.S.T., Fine Art Security Transportation)
    Lucien Goldschmidt, Inc.
    Luers, William H.
  - M. H. de Young Memorial Museum, 2001-2005 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Mac Dowell Colony, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Mailing Lists, 1995-1997 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Mailing Lists, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Mangel Gallery/Benjamin Mangel Gallery, 1983-2000,undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Mangravite, Peppino, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Marble Care and Repair, 1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Marin, John (book and exhibitions), 1968-1992, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Martha Lincoln Gallery - Massachusetts College of Art, 1970-1996 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Martha Lincoln Gallery
    Massachusetts College of Art
  - Mattatuck Historical Society, 1979-1997, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Matter, Mercedes - Miller, Stephen, 1968-1997, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
    Matter, Mercedes
    Maxwell, William (See also: Correspondence, Personal, Box 1, F 21)
    May, Stephanie
    Metropolitan Museum of Art
    Michael H. Lord Gallery
    Miller
    Miller, Ingeborg Morath
    Miller, Stephen (re: Kay Sage)
  - Minnesota Museum of Art - Murch, Katharine (Mrs. Walter T.), 1967-1989 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    Minnesota Museum of Art
    Modena, Bruno
    Montclair Art Museum
    Morgan, Ken
    Motherwell, Robert (See also: Correspondence, Personal, Box 1, F 21)
    Mulas, Ugo
    Murch, Katharine (Mrs. Walter T.)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1990-1997 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Houston, 1983-1998 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1995-1999, undated, (See also: Correspondence, Business, Box 1, F 20; Correspondence, Personal, Box 1, F 21) (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - "My Insomnia" (fan mail re: Gray's poem in The New York Times), 1976 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Nabakov, Dominique and Nicolas - Nakian, Paul S., 1974-1979 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    Nabakov, Dominique and Nicolas
    Nakian, Paul S.
  - "Narcissus in Chaos" correspondence, 1958-1961, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - National Collection of Fine Arts/National Museum of American Art, Smithsonian Institution, 1968-1997 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Neuberger Museum of Art, State University of New York, College at Purchase, 1973-1999, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 38-39)
  - Neuberger, Roy, 1973-1987 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - New Britain Museum of American Art, 1981-2003, (See also: Promised Gifts to Museums, Box 3, F 59) (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - New York Foundation for the Arts - New York Graphic Society Ltd., 1970-1991 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    New York Foundation for the Arts
    New York Graphic Society Ltd
  - New York Studio School, 1972-1977, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - The New Yorker - Newark Museum, 1973-1987 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    The New Yorker
    Newark Museum
  - Newman, Barnett, 1968-1989, undated, (See also: Correspondence, Personal, Box 1, F 21) (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Nicholson, John and Carol Grim - Ogden City Schools, 1968-2001, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
    Nicholson, John and Carol Grim
    Nina Freudenheim Gallery
    Norman, Dorothy
    Northeast Magazine
    Northwest Center for Family Services and Mental Health
    Norton Museum of Art
    Obalk, Hector
    Ogden City Schools
  - Oklahoma Art Center, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Orozco, José Clemente - Osborn, Robert, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    Orozco, José Clemente
    Osborn, Robert
  - Outdoor Art at the Station, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Outdoor Art at the Station, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Partisan Review - Pincus-Witten, Robert, 1979-1997, undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
    Partisan Review (See also: "Seduction and Betrayal of Contemporary Art," Box 4, F 26)
    Penn, Irving
    Perls Galleries
    Phillips Collection
    Pincus-Witten, Robert
  - Politicians and Political Campaigns, 1968-1990 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Ponce de Leon, Michael, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Pratt Graphic Art Center, 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Pratt Center for Contemporary Printmaking/Pratt Graphics Center, 1967-1986, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Princeton University (Box 3)
    - Alumni Collectors Exhibition, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Art History Notes, Quizzes, Examinations, 1936-1940 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Art Museum, 1970-1991, (See also: Correspondence, Business, Box 1, F 20; Promised Gifts to Museums, Box 3, F 59) (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Promised Gifts to Museums, 1973-2005 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    Colby College
    Neuberger Museum of Art
    New Britain Museum of American Art
    Rhode Island School of Design Museum of Art
    Wadsworth Atheneum
    Whitney Museum of American Art
    Worcester Art Museum
  - "Questions You Should Ask Your Framer and Answers You Should Get" - Reynal, Jeanne, 1972, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    "Questions You Should Ask Your Framer and Answers You Should Get" (Tamarind Lithography Workshop, Inc.)
    Reynal, Jeanne, 1972
  - Rhode Island School of Design (Box 4)
    - College, 1968-2000, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Museum, 1969-1997, undated, (See also: Promised Gifts, Box 3, F 59) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Richard Feigen Gallery, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Richter, Fridel, 1972-1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Richter, Hans (See also: Von Hofacker, Marion, Box 4, F 51) (Box 4)
    - Book (includes permissions), 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1940, 1965-1975, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Estate, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Exhibitions (Neuberger Museum, Rhode Island School of Design, Stamford Museum, University of Iowa), 1971-1995 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Inventories and Lists of Art Work, 1965-1994, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Rickey, George - Riley, Bridget, 1984-1994, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Rickey, George
    Riley, Bridget
  - Robert L. Kidd Associates, Incorporated, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Roberts, Colette - Rorimer, Kay (Mrs. James T.), 1968-1995, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Roberts, Colette
    Robertson, Bryan
    Robinson, Joan
    Rockefeller, Nelson A.
    Rorimer, Kay (Mrs. James T.)
  - Rose, Barbara, 1988-1996, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Roth, Philip - Rothschild, Philippe, 1985-1991 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Roth, Philip
    Roth, Ronnie (Mrs. Marvin)
    Rothschild, Philippe
  - Rowley, George (includes transcript of conversation with Gray about Chinese and Western composition), 1955 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Royal Globe Insurance Co. Claim, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Rubenstein, Angelica Zander - Saidenberg Gallery Inc., 1965-1994 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Rubenstein, Angelica Zander
    Safe Return Amnesty Committee Art Show/Benefit
    Saidenberg Gallery Inc.
  - St. John the Divine, Cathedral Church of, 1974-1990, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - St. John's Parish (Washington, CT), 1971, (See also: Vestments, box 4, F 44) (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - St. Paul's School, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - St. Peter's Church - Schapiro, Meyer, 1967-2000, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    St. Peter's Church (New York)
    Samuel, Ruth (Mrs. Sanford)
    San Francisco State College
    Sanders, Charles
    Sandra Gering Gallery
    Schapiro, Meyer
  - Schmit, Dorothee (re: Villon), 1999-2001, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Schrag, Karl - Scull, Robert C., 1968-2000 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Schrag, Karl
    Schrager, Felice and Louis
    Scott, Martha
    Scoville, Ann
    Scull, Robert C.
  - Sculpture, 1971-1977, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - "The Seduction and Betrayal of Contemporary Art," 1988-1989, (See also: Partisan Review, Box 3, F 51) (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Sharon Creative Arts Foundation, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Shearer, Rhonda (re: Marcel Duchamp), 1998 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Sheldon Memorial Art Gallery and Sculpture Garden - Sloan, Eric, 1988-2000, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
    Sheldon Memorial Art Gallery and Sculpture Garden, University of Nebraska
    Shestack, Alan
    Shippee Gallery
    Skjelford Associates
    Sloan, Eric
  - Smith, David (Box 4)
    - Book (includes permissions), 1966-1999, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 30-31)
    - Book (thank you letters), 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - General, 1967-1987 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Smith, John E., 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Sneed Gallery/Sneed-Hillman Gallery, 1969-1987, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Solo Press, Inc. - Staempfli Gallery, 1964-1997, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
    Solo Press, Inc.
    Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum
    Staempfli Gallery
  - State University of New York at Albany, Art Gallery - Thaw, Eugene Victor, 1967-1989, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
    State University of New York at Albany, Art Gallery
    State University of New York, College at Purchase (See also: Neuberger Museum of Art, Box 3, F 38-39)
    Steckel, Marie-Monique
    Steegmuller, Francis
    Steig, William
    Steinberg, Leo
    Stephan, John
    Stetson, John C.
    Stevens, Leonard A.
    Styron, William, (See also: Correspondence, Personal, Box 1, F 21)
    Swan, Simone Withers
    Talbot, William
    Thaw, Eugene Victor
  - Thomas Gilcrease Institute of American History and Art, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Thomson, Virgil - 3K s.n.c. Stamperia D'Arte, 1969-1982 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    Thomson, Virgil (re: Marcel Duchamp)
    3K s.n.c. Stamperia D'Arte
  - Threnody, 1973-2002, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Trevor-Roper, Alexandra - University of Connecticut, 1974-1992, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
    Trevor-Roper, Alexandra
    Tyler Graphics Ltd.
    Typefaces
    United States Holocaust Museum
    University of Connecticut (See also: William Benton Museum of Art, box 5, F 6)
  - University of Hartford, 1984-2001 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Vermont Studio Center, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Vestments, 1975-1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
    St. James Church, Farmington, CT
    St. John's Parish, Washington, CT
    Episcopal Diocese of Connecticut (See also: Walmsley, Arthur E., box 4, F 53)
  - Vicente, Harriet (Mrs. Esteban), 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 45)